Javier García Salcedo

♣ Philosopher | Logician | Full-Stack Developer

J (52) 5555088893

■ jagasal@icloud.com

in javiergss

Professional Profile

I am a philosopher and a logician graduated from the National Autonomous University of Mexico and the University of Toulouse II, and a natural communicator. I've worked in academia for 15+ years and successfully instilled my passion for mathematical logic and the humanities in a great many of my students. Recently, I have obtained my MIT/xPRO professional certificate in full-stack development with MERN, and I am presently pursuing new professional paths as a front- and back-end developer.

Work Experience

Modern American School Aug 2015 - Present: Logic and Philosophy Professor I deliver courses on logic, ethics and history of philosophy. I provide my students with the analytical skills and conceptual resources for them to develop a unique and robust interpretation of themselves and their place in the contemporary world.

Technological Autonomous Institute of Mexico Aug 2011 - May 2020: Assistant Professor I delivered the courses of Modern and Contemporary Western History and Philosophy, as well as Political and Economic Issues of Contemporary Western Civilization. I instilled in my students a deeper appreciation of the relevance of philosophy to their technical and professional activities. I advised several undergraduate theses in applied mathematics and law.

National Autonomous University of Mexico Aug 2010 - June 2019: Assistant Professor I imparted courses on the philosophy of mathematics, many-valued logics, propositional and first-order logic, propositional and first-order modal logic, set theory and the meta-theory of propositional and first-order logic. I coordinated several seminars, and advised logic and philosophy undergraduate and graduate theses.

Elena Poniatowska's Archives Jan 2006 - June 2007: Research Assistant I coordinated the team conducting the journalistic research that underpins Elena Poniatowska's "Amanecer en el Zócalo. Los 50 días que confrontaron a México" (Planeta, 2007).

Entropía Humana S.C. Jan 2003 - Sept 2005: Cultural Manager I was in charge of managing the company's musical portfolio.

¡Río Loco! Festival Sept 2002 - July 2004: Artistic Advisor I appraised the work of international musicians and assessed their relevance to the festival definitive line-up.

Canal Sud Radio 92.2 FM

Nov 2002 - Jan 2003: Radio Producer, Host and DJ
I was charged with the musical curatorship of the show 'Catemaco' and the research for its news segment.
I was also a host of the show.

Education

National Autonomous University of Mexico 2003 - 2007: Master in Philosophy and Logic Thesis title: "Wittgenstein's notion of Linguistic Understanding". Thesis advisor: Salma Saab, PhD.

University of Toulouse II 2000 - 2002: Master in Philosophy of Language Thesis title: "Form and Usage in Wittgenstein's Philosophy". Thesis advisor: Xavier Verley, PhD.

University of Toulouse II

1997 - 2000: Bachelor's Degree (Major: Philosophy)

Lycée Français Louis Pasteur

1981 - 1996: *High School Degree*

\'> Technical Skills

✓ MERN stack

✓ React.js

✓ MongoDB

✓ JavaScript

✓ Node.js

✓ Express.js

✓ HTML5

✓ GitHub

✓ Logical analysis

✓ CSS3

✓ Docker

✓ Stripe ✓ Swagger

✓ Strapi

✓ DigitalOcean

✓ Formal semantics

***** Certifications

- # Full-Stack Development with MERN (MIT/xPRO, 2023)
- * Project-Based Learning (UNAM, 2022)
- * Sixty years of AI (UNAM, 2022)
- * Certificate in Logic (UNAM, 2004)

A Languages

- Spanish Native
- French Bilingual Proficiency
- English Bilingual Proficiency
- Portuguese Professional Working Proficiency

Published Papers

- Review of "The Writer's Workshop: Imitating Your Way to Better Writing", by G. Roper, in *Estudios*, ITAM, Mexico City, 116, 2016.
- "La escalera de Wittgenstein", in *Estudios*, ITAM, Mexico City, 112, 2015.
- Translation into Spanish of the article "Scepticisme Cartésien et Scepticisme Huméen", by Pascal Engel, in *Dudas filosóficas. Ensayos sobre escepticismo antiguo, moderno y contemporáneo*, A. Cíntora y J. Ornelas (eds.), Gedisa/UAM, Mexico City, 2014.
- Review of Bertrand Russell y al análisis filosófico a partir de "On Denoting", by Silvio Pinto (ed.), in Crítica, UNAM, Mexico City, 42-126, 2014.
- "La question du silence dans le Tractatus", in Les Cahiers d'Adèle, Toulouse,1, 2008.
- "Atribución de creencias justificativas para una predicción con reservas", in *Ergo*, University of Veracruz, Xalapa,19, 2006.